CURRICULUM VITAE



Barrirero, Exequiel

Address: Av. Colón 4933 (5000) Córdoba, Argentina

Mobile: +54-9-351-5510132

E-mail: exequielrafaela@gmail.com

Marital Status: Single Nationality: Argentinian

Date of birth: 02/07/86 – Rafaela, Santa Fe

CARRER SUMMARY

Exequiel is an IT passionate Telecommunications Engineer with over 5 years of professional experience administering, configuring, monitoring and supporting IT Production Infrastructures. During his career he has worked in several Mobile Communications, VoIP Security and Software development projects mainly under Open-Source Linux techs as Support Engineer, SysAdmin, DevOps, IP/MPLS Project Leader and Certification Tech Instructor.

Multicultural and foreign experiences have endowed him with proven communication skills. He can speak three languages fluently, effectively use active listening to improve team work, knowledge sharing and report to upper management.

He loves learning as much as he enjoys teaching.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Postgraduate & Diplomas

(2015 - 2017 expected)

Computer Science GNU/Linux Operative System Diploma – Cordoba National University (UNC) – Córdoba, Argentina.

University Studies

(2006 - 2016)

Bachelor's Degree (Engineer's degree), Telecommunications Engineering GPA: 7,55 (over 10) – Blas Pascal University – Córdoba, Argentina.

(2010)

Exchange Undergraduate Program (fall semester) - Field of Study: Computer Science GPA: 3,67 / 4 (Earned Dean's Dr. Boehman list distinction for fall 2010, School of Arts & Sciences) – University of Richmond – Virginia, United States.

(2005 - 2009)

Certificate: University Telecommunications Technician – GPA: 7,63 (over 10) Blas Pascal University – Córdoba, Argentina.

IT SKILLS

- Linux System Administration: Debian, Ubuntu, Centos.
- Linux Services: Apache2 WebServer, NFS Server, Bind9 DNS.
- Automation/ Configuration mgmt / Scripting: Bash, Python Fabric & Vagrant.
- Programming: C, Java J2SE, Python.
- Virtualization: VirtualBox, VMware, AWS EC2, AWS ELB, AWS ASG.
- Version Control SW: GIT (GitHub)/ SVN (SourgeForge) / Mercurial (TortoiseHg).
- Networking: IP Routers, Tcpdump, IP/MPLS and TCP/IP Protocols (Sockets).
- Transmission technologies (DWDM/CWDM, OTN, SDH/PDH).
- Monitoring: Nagios (SNMP checkSNMP & NRPE Agent).
- Computer Security: Iptables, Nmap, VoIP-SIP Honeypots.
- Technical writing: LaTeX

LANGUAGES

Spanish (Native or bilingual proficiency)

English (Full professional proficiency)

(2010) TOEFL iBT (Test of English as a Foreign Language internet-Based Test)

August 2010 - License ETS ID: 5197872 - Score: 94

(2003) Cambridge University Certificate: FCE (First Certificate of English)

December 2003 - Grade: C

Portuguese (Full professional proficiency)

Advanced Writing, Listening, Speaking and Reading comprehension skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE



(September 2013 – Present)

Transport Network Support Engineer – Operations and support of the fixed and mobile (2G/3G/LTE) Claro Argentina, Uruguay and Paraguay transport network. Aptitudes and skills: Acceptance, configuration, monitoring and incident resolving over different transmission technologies: Fiber Optics, Microwave Radio Links, Satellite Links. IP/MPLS, SDH/PDH, DWDM/CWDM, OTN – (Alcatel / Ciena-Nortel / Ericsson / Huawei / Nera-Ceragon / Nokia / Siemens / Tellabs / ZTE) – Claro AR (América Móvil - AMX Argentina S.A.) – Córdoba, Argentina.

Technical Trainer – Coordinating and delivering an "Alcatel-Lucent Scalable IP Networks Exam" course during 2015/2016, preparing internal company colleagues that pass the exam. Hence, achieving the **ALU Network Routing Specialist I (NRS I - 4A0-100) Certification**. Upon successful completion of this course, they were familiar with the basics of TCP/IP, routing, routing protocols, IP addressing, Ethernet and IP/MPLS services – **Claro AR** (América Móvil - AMX Argentina S.A.) – Córdoba, Argentina.

UNIVERSIDAD BLAS PASCAL UBDP USDAY SABOY FALSON

(March 2012 – March 2014)

Computer Security Researching Auxiliary – Implementation, deployment, testing and functional developments over Artemisa (Open-Source Back-End VoIP Honeypot - http://artemisa.sourceforge.net/). Skills: GNU Linux, Python programming, SVN (SourceForge), Asterisk & SER (VoIP-SIP), Networking, NFS, Computer Security – Science and Technology Department & Blas Pascal University – Córdoba, Argentina.

(January 2013 – September 2013)

- Ensure the high availability and redundancy of Intel's application services (Intel Cloud Services Platform) and backend of Intel's web services (Intel Context Sensing, Intel AppUp, Intel Identity Services, Intel Update Manager).
- Administration of Linux and Windows 2003, 2008, 2012 Servers.
- Amazon Cloud Services (EC2, ASG, ELB, Security Groups, VPC).
- Automation using Python Fabric, Bash and Powershell Scripting.
- Installing and configuring real time monitoring of production environments with Nagios (Webinjec & SNMP plugins), Centreon, Nagvis, Thruk.
- Experience on agile methodologies (Kanban and Scrum) to administer, troubleshoot and deploy different environments (Production, Testing, Staging, Developing), involved in software development process using Continuous integration and Continuous deployment (Mercurial, SVN, Bamboo, Jira, Confluence) Intel Corporation (thru Experis), Córdoba, Argentina.

(February 2011 – July 2011)

IT Midrange Operations (MRO) – 1st level of Servers administration. Monitoring and troubleshooting on Unix (Solaris) / Linux (RedHat) and MS Windows Server (High availability 24x7 environments). ITIL Incident Mgmt / Change Mgmt – **Hewlett-Packard** Córdoba, Argentina.

CONGRESS AND COURSES ATTENDANCE

(2014/2015)

- DWDM 1830 PSS Management 5620 SAM (TOS36028) **Alcatel-Lucent/Nokia** University 24hs.
- Network Routing Specialist I (NRS I) Certification Scalable IP Networks exam (4A0-100) (Link) **Alcatel-Lucent/Nokia**, License SRC ID: SRC192147 Cert ID: 6982.
- WDM Networks: Fundamentals, Design, Operations & Maintenance w/ Lab Ceragon Netwokrs Ltd. Training 40hs.
- **Ericsson** MINI-LINK TN Operation, Maintenance & Adv. Troubleshooting (LZU1088414-R2A & LZU1087997-R2A) RLAM Learning Services Claro AR (AMX Argentina S.A.) Córdoba, Argentina 40hr. (2010/2009)
- Linux Network and Servers course (Debian GNU/Linux Squid proxy routing IPtables Apache2 web serv Bind9 DNS SquirrelMail) C.UNIX IT consulting firm (www.cunix.com.ar) Córdoba, Argentina 24hr.

- Computer Security course with Open Source tools (Cryptography and ciphers fundamentals OpenSSL Nmap TCPdump GnuPG arpspoof MIM IPTables FW Builder) IEEE Blas Pascal University 16hr.
- CCNA (**Cisco** Certified Network Associate) Nw Fundamentals, Routing, Switching y Wireless LAN National Technologic University (UTN) Córdoba, Argentina 120hr.